English subtitles
You scared me to death!
What were you doing?
I was just appreciating this cool song
I just downloaded off the net.
You are so busted
You’re not allowed to steal music
off the net. It’s illegal.
I’m going to the cops!
What is with you? No, it’s ok.
This is a track I got from Opsound
So who’s Opsound?
No, Opsound is a website.
You’re allowed to get music that
use Creative Commons licences.
You only can’t download music
if you don’t have permission.
Creative Commons means you can.
Keep talking or I’m going to the cops.
You were an annoying baby, weren’t you?
Keep talking…
Well anything that’s copyrighted ...
you need to get permission to use right? right
But anything licensed under
Creative Commons licences
means you’ve already got permission…
So you can use it for anything?
Not exactly.
The licence tells you what you can do.
If someone makes a song and they decide ...
Hey this is cool! I’m gonna let other
people use it! They can
licence the songin a way that says
exactly what others can and can’t do.
How?
Well, Creative Commons protects
the work in four main ways.
... Which  is just a big word that means
you have to put the author’s name
on anywhere you use their work
and ...  which means you can’t
make money off the song
So I can’t sell  it and buy  a car?
No.
and then there’s ... which means ...
you can’t change the song in any way
but there’s also  ... which means
you can change the song how ever you like ...
as long as you licence in the same way
So, if I stick to whatever the artist wants  ...
I can download whatever I want for free?
Yep.  You can!
So…  if I made the best song in the world ...
and decided that I was ok with
people sharing it just because ...
if people didn’t hear it their lives
wouldn’t be worth living because ...
it was so cool…
Ye-ah, I get the point.
How do they know how it’s licensed?
you have to put a link
next to the mp3 of your song
I think you mean the best song in the world
Stop that!
Say iiit!
You just put a a link next
to the mp3 of
the best song in the world
Alright!
And all people  have to do is
click on the link and it will
take them to a list of what they
can and can’t do with your song.
Ok. So where can I download
some of these songs?
They’re all over the web.
But a few good places are…
You got a pen?
Why?
So you can write these sites down.
I don’t need to.
Why not?
Because they’ll appear above
your head as you talk.
Are you serious?!
Give it a try.
Creative Commons has an online
music community called CC Mixter.
See.
That’s cool. And Opsound like I said before.
This is so much fun!
Let’s see how many I can get!
Whatever gets you going.
Umm, there’s also Dmusic, SoundClick
and Magnatune ... AND!
In some cases you can do more
with them than just play the songs
If the licence says so,
you can sample, mash and remix music.
and you better believe I WILL!!!
Well, I’m going to download some music
for free and not illegally. Ah hum.
Uh umm, you can download
other stuff as well.
Really?!
Yeah!
Anything that is created can be licensed.
Stories? Photos? Drawings? Websites?
Yep! All of them!
And movies. And sounds.
And weblogs. And books. And articles.
That’s a lot of stuff. How do I find it?
Creative Commons has its own search
engine: search.creativecommons.org
You’ll find heaps of cool stuff.
That’s really cool. I’ll go check it out.
Ok. Have fun.
Can I report you to the cops anyway?
Just because?
What’s wrong with you is no little thing.
Subtitles: François Schnell
from the original script