Where the devil should this Romeo be?
Came he not home to-night?
Not to his father's;
I spoke with his man.
Ah, that same pale hard-hearted wench, that Rosaline.
Torments him so, that he will sure run mad.
Tybalt, the kinsman of old Capulet,
Hath sent a letter to his father's house.
A challenge, on my life.
Romeo will answer it.
Any man that can write may answer a letter.
Nay, he will answer the letter's master,
how he dares, being dared.
Alas poor Romeo! he is already dead;
stabbed with a white wench's black eye;
shot through the ear with a love-song;
the very pin of his heart cleft with the blind bow-boy's
butt-shaft: and is he a man to encounter Tybalt?
Why, what is Tybalt?
More than prince of cats, I can tell you.
O, he is the courageous captain of compliments.
He fights as you sing prick-song,
keeps time, distance, and proportion;
rests me his minim rest, one, two, and the third...
...in your bosom: the very butcher of a silk button,
a duellist, a duellist;
a gentleman of the very first house,
of the first and second cause...
ah, the immortal passado! the punto reverso! the hai!
The what?